start with an empty webapp, only show Timeline and Annotation (both collapsed)
Mouseover Tracker dropdown: each bird has a tracker id. We'll use 355, a Lesser black backed gull a.k.a a seagull
Mouseover 'From' calendar: select 2010-06-28
Mouseover 'From' time: select 00:00:00
Mouseover 'To' calendar: select 2010-06-29
Mouseover 'To' time: select 06:00:00
Mouseover Timeline: expand Timeline
click Load tracker button
Expand timeline
The bird has different behavior at different times: the colors show what each behavior is
Expand the Annotations widget
Let's see how those annotations come to be
Let's look at the gray area, which represents the bird sitting on the ground
If a bird is sitting on the ground you expect both its speed and its altitude to be low
Let's visualize some additional tracker data to see if that is true
Mouseover 'Windows' button
Check 'speed'
So the speed is low for this time period
Let's add altitude
Mouseover 'Windows' button, check 'altitude'
So altitude is also low for this time period.
But it's a bit difficult to see, let's make it bigger
Maximize altitude widget
The blue line represents GPS altitude
The blue area represents the altitude based looking up the surface elevation at the bird's location
They are very close. Ergo the bird is sitting on the ground
But wait there is more
These little gray lines...
Mouseover Timeline plot gray lines
...mean that an accelerometer measurement was taken at that time.
Let's look at the data
string