start with an empty webapp, only show Timeline and Annotation (both collapsed)
Mouseover Tracker dropdown: each bird has a tracker id. We'll use 355, a Lesser black backed gull a.k.a a seagull
Mouseover 'From' calendar: select 2010-06-28
Mouseover 'From' time: select 00:00:00
Mouseover 'To' calendar: select 2010-06-29
Mouseover 'To' time: select 06:00:00
Mouseover Timeline: expand Timeline
click Load tracker button
...wait for data to load...
The bird has different behavior at different times: the colors show what each behavior is
...a so-called 'annotation', such as 'flapping' or 'sitting'
The second row is 'Timepoints' -- we'll get to that in a minute
Expand the Annotations widget
A chronological list of how the bird behaved...
...corresponding to the data in the graph.
Let's take a closer look at this gray area, which represents the bird sitting on the ground.
If a bird is sitting on the ground you expect both its speed and its altitude to be low
Let's visualize some additional tracker data to see if that is true.
Mouseover 'Windows' button
Check 'speed'
So the speed is low for this time period
Never mind this part, there's a bug here
The important part is that the speed is close to zero at this time.
Let's add altitude
So altitude is also low for this time period.
But wait there is more...
These little gray lines...
...mean that an accelerometer measurement was taken at that time.
Let's look at the accelerometer data.
Accelerometer measurements are taken in bursts of a few seconds, using an increased measurement frequency.
The lower widget shows the 6 bursts closest to the current time.
Accelerometer shows acceleration in 3-D.
Coincidentally, the sensor is oriented almost exactly horizontal when the bird is sitting.
You can see this in the acceleration data: green is vertical...
...which registers about 1.0 G...
...while the other axes register about 0.0 G.